<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>dissertations | Christine Bauer</title><link>https://christinebauer.eu/tag/dissertations/</link><atom:link href="https://christinebauer.eu/tag/dissertations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>dissertations</description><generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2023 Christine Bauer</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 02:00:06 +0200</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://christinebauer.eu/media/sharing.png</url><title>dissertations</title><link>https://christinebauer.eu/tag/dissertations/</link></image><item><title>Three dissertations within a month</title><link>https://christinebauer.eu/post/20231213_dissertations/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 02:00:06 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://christinebauer.eu/post/20231213_dissertations/</guid><description>&lt;p>What a rich expansion to my library: 3 dissertations within a month!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I had the pleasure being on the committees for Yu Liang and Darius Afchar.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The title of Yu&amp;rsquo;s dissertation is &amp;lsquo;Supporting Personalized Music Exploration through a Genre Exploration Recommender&amp;rsquo;. The defense took place in the nice chapel at Jheronimus Academy of Data Science. It was also the first time I wore a &amp;rsquo;toga&amp;rsquo; at a Dutch defense. (And for those interested: We followed the procedures of Eindhoven University of Technology.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Darius&amp;rsquo; dissertation is entitled &amp;lsquo;Interpretable Music Recommender Systems&amp;rsquo;. The defense took place at Sorbonne Université. Of course, lots of Deezer people were around because the research was done with Deezer. I had the pleasure asking the most difficult questions of the day 😆. Darius was still talking to me afterwards; so, it must have been okay. 😉&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Roger&amp;rsquo;s work has the title &amp;lsquo;Metric Optimization and Mainstream Bias Mitigation in Recommender Systems&amp;rsquo;. While I was not part of the committee and did not attend the defense, Roger gladly handed over one copy of his dissertation. He even did that personally after Yu&amp;rsquo;s defense.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All three have done great work. And also the book covers look cool!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Congratulations to the new doctors 🥳&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>