<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>PhD | Christine Bauer</title><link>https://christinebauer.eu/tag/phd/</link><atom:link href="https://christinebauer.eu/tag/phd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>PhD</description><generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2024 Christine Bauer</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://christinebauer.eu/media/sharing.png</url><title>PhD</title><link>https://christinebauer.eu/tag/phd/</link></image><item><title>PhD position at Paris Lodron University Salzburg</title><link>https://christinebauer.eu/post/20240130_phd_position/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christinebauer.eu/post/20240130_phd_position/</guid><description>&lt;p>To strengthen our interdisciplinary research team, we seek a PhD candidate (30h/week; for 4 years) with a focus on &lt;strong>recommender systems&lt;/strong> and an interest in &lt;strong>fairness&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Candidates are expected to integrate well into a genuinely interdisciplinary research setting and share a strong interest in the topic of recommender systems. Ideally, they will focus on one or more of the following areas:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>fairness in recommender systems;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>music recommender systems; or&lt;/li>
&lt;li>societal implications of recommender systems.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>This position is part of the &amp;lsquo;Excellence in Digital Sciences and Interdisciplinary Technologies&amp;rsquo; (EXDIGIT) initiative at the &lt;a href="https://www.plus.ac.at/digital-and-analytical-sciences/?lang=en" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Faculty of Digital and Analytical Sciences&lt;/a> at Paris Lodron University Salzburg, Austria.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="./phd_job.pdf">Full vacancy description&lt;/a>
&lt;figure >
&lt;div class="d-flex justify-content-center">
&lt;div class="w-100" >&lt;img src="./phd_job_featured.png" alt="Pic of full vacancy description; full text in the linked pdf above." loading="lazy" data-zoomable width="248" height="159" />&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For questions related to the position, feel free to address me directly via e-mail. Applications have to be sent to the e-mail address as specified in the job description.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vacant positions (PhD and Postdoc level) in my team at Paris Lodron University Salzburg</title><link>https://christinebauer.eu/post/20230623_exdigit_jobs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2023 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://christinebauer.eu/post/20230623_exdigit_jobs/</guid><description>&lt;p>I am happy to announce that we have several vacant positions (at PhD and Postdoc level) to work with us within the framework of the EXDIGIT Research College at the Paris-Lodron University of Salzburg.
EXDIGIT stands for &amp;ldquo;Excellence in Digital Sciences and Interdisciplinary Technologies&amp;rdquo;. In this interdisciplinary endeavor, we emphasize bridging the existing research areas and represented disciplines at the faculty.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I seek candidates to work with me on topics related to &lt;strong>fairness of algorithmic decision-making&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>adaptation and personalization&lt;/strong>&amp;mdash;specifically in the &lt;strong>recommender systems&lt;/strong> field. Interest in researching these topics in the music or media sector is a particular asset.
I expect the ability and interest to employ both &lt;strong>computational research approaches&lt;/strong> (e.g., offline evaluation in recommender systems research, data analysis of large data sets) as well as &lt;strong>experimental (user) studies&lt;/strong> (e.g., controlled experiments in the lab or online settings).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The closing date for applications is 31 July 2023.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="./EXDIGIT_C4C_ResearchCollege_deutsch.pdf">Full vacancy description (in German)&lt;/a>&lt;br>
&lt;a href="./C4C_ResearchCollege_final_EN.pdf">Full vacancy description (in English)&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For questions related to the positions on my topics, please address me directly via e-mail.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>In addition to positions related to my favorite research topics, the EXDIGIT Research College has further vacancies on a wide set of topics (both at PhD and Postdoc level). For details, please refer to the full vacancy description.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CfP: RecSys 2023 Doctoral Symposium</title><link>https://christinebauer.eu/post/20230215_recsys2023ds/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 02:00:06 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://christinebauer.eu/post/20230215_recsys2023ds/</guid><description>&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://recsys.acm.org/recsys23/call/#content-tab-1-4-tab" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Call for Papers&lt;/a> for the Doctoral Symposium at &lt;a href="https://recsys.acm.org/recsys23/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">RecSys 2023&lt;/a> in Singapore is online.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This year, I have the honor co-chairing the symposium with &lt;a href="http://www.di.uniba.it/~swap/index.php?n=Membri.CataldoMusto" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Cataldo Musto&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://staff.ustc.edu.cn/~hexn/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> Xiangnan He&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We are looking forward to receiving lots of submissions. It is always a pleasure supporting young academic talent in their PhD journey.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Deadline is May 23rd, 2023.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Karlijn Dinnissen has successfully passed her first-year assessment</title><link>https://christinebauer.eu/post/20230209_gonogo_karlijn/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 02:00:06 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://christinebauer.eu/post/20230209_gonogo_karlijn/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today, &lt;a href="https://karlijnd.github.io" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Karlijn Dinnissen&lt;/a> had the first-year assessment of her PhD plan. As expected, she successfully passed this stage. The external reviewer, &lt;a href="https://md.ekstrandom.net" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Michael Ekstrand&lt;/a>, confirmed that she is well on track in her PhD journey. Congratulations to Karlijn! And thank you to Michael Ekstrand for serving as a reviewer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Karlijn entitled her presentation &amp;ldquo;Improving Fairness and Transparency for Item Providers in Multi-Stakeholder Music Recommender Systems&amp;rdquo;. The item providers are the artists&amp;mdash;in case you wondered. :-)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Panelist at the Doctoral Symposium of RecSys 2022: PhD and career journey</title><link>https://christinebauer.eu/talks/pl02_recsys2022ds/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christinebauer.eu/talks/pl02_recsys2022ds/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>