<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>year in review | Christine Bauer</title><link>https://christinebauer.eu/tag/year-in-review/</link><atom:link href="https://christinebauer.eu/tag/year-in-review/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>year in review</description><generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2024 Christine Bauer</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 02:00:06 +0200</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://christinebauer.eu/media/sharing.png</url><title>year in review</title><link>https://christinebauer.eu/tag/year-in-review/</link></image><item><title>Year in Review 2023</title><link>https://christinebauer.eu/post/20240107_2023yearinreview/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 02:00:06 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://christinebauer.eu/post/20240107_2023yearinreview/</guid><description>&lt;p>Inspired by the end-of-year reviews of &lt;a href="https://md.ekstrandom.net/blog/2023/12/2023" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Michael Ekstrand&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://log.lab.matkelly.com/year-in-review-2023" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Matt Kelly&lt;/a>, I thought it might be a good idea to do that too.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It has been a pretty full year with many ups&amp;ndash; -yet, also downs.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="my-personal-highlights">My personal highlights&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Starting as a full professor at PLUS, advocating interdisciplinary research as part of the EXDIGIT initiative.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I had the honor of giving the &lt;a href="https://christinebauer.eu/talks/kn05_ismir2023/">opening keynote address at ISMIR&lt;/a>. ISMIR was an amazing experience.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Traveling a lot: From this year&amp;rsquo;s home countries (Austria and The Netherlands), I traveled for work to Denmark, France, Germany, Italy, Singapore, Switzerland, UK.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Reviving the collaboration with &lt;a href="https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=WQglBowAAAAJ" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Andrés Ferraro&lt;/a> on bias mitigation in music recommender systems. We are going strong 💪&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="publications">Publications&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1 journal paper (TORS)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 full conference papers (UMAP, ISMIR, HICSS); thereof 2 with PhD researchers, one of them nominated for Best Student Paper Award&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 short conference paper (CHIGREECE) with PhD researchers&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 demo paper (CHIIR) with bachelor students&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 full workshop paper (MuRS)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 proceedings (PERSPECTIVES)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Dagstuhl report&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 event reports (PERSPECTIVES, Dagstuhl Seminar, Allyship panel)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 abstract (IIR)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Further, 3 journal papers are under review or in revision state.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="keynotes-talks-and-panels">Keynotes, talks, and panels&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>3 keynotes: ISMIR, Women in RecSys, IIR&lt;/li>
&lt;li>4 invited talks&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 workshop presentation&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Panelist at the Inclusion Panel at ISMIR&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Moderation of the Allyship Panel at CHI&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="awards-and-nominations">Awards and nominations&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>For the &lt;a href="https://christinebauer.eu/publications/zangerle-2022-fevr/">CSUR paper with Eva Zangerle&lt;/a>, we received the Women in RecSys 2023 Journal Paper of the Year Award (&amp;ldquo;Senior&amp;rdquo;).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The UMAP paper with Karlijn Dinnissen was nominated for the Best Student Paper Award.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Nominated for the Best Reviewer award at UMAP.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="teaching">Teaching&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Started teaching Advanced Contextual Interfaces in the Joint HCI Master of PLUS and FHS&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Guest lectures at the University of Regensburg and TU Wien&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 sessions at the RecSys 2023 Summer School, two of them with Martijn C. Willemsen&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Member of the Education and Advisory Committee for Information Science Master Programs at UU&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ongoing: Member of an Honorary Appointment Committee at the University of Siegen&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="advising-and-supervising-phd-researchers">Advising and supervising PhD researchers&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>I am happy that I keep serving as the co-promotor of &lt;a href="https://marloesvredenborg.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Marloes Vredenborg&lt;/a> (UU).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>While not officially acting in a (co-)promotor role, I keep working with &lt;a href="https://www.uu.nl/staff/AvanKasteren/Publications" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Anouk van Kasteren&lt;/a> (UU); this comes quite handy, as Marloes and Anouk are working on the same project.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>This year, I started collaborating with &lt;a href="https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=-vmPHIUAAAAJ" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Daniele Pretolesi&lt;/a> (AIT) as the secondary supervisor.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I supervised Karlijn Dinnissen (UU) until including her successful first-year assessment of her PhD plan.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="service--organization">Service &amp;amp; organization&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Independent Ethics Advisor of the EU project &lt;a href="https://www.openmuse.eu" target="_blank" rel="noopener">OpenMusE&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>WiMIR mentoring 2023&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Co-Chairing:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>PhD Symposium Co-Chair at CIKM 2023, with Haiming Liu&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Doctoral Symposium Co-Chair at RecSys 2023, with Cataldo Musto and Xiangnan He&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Allyship Co-Chair at CHI 2023, with Siobahn Day Grady and assisted by Anouk van Kasteren&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Workshop Co-Organizer of PERSPECTIVES 2023 at RecSys 2023, with Alan Said and Eva Zangerle&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Dagstuhl Seminar Co-Organizer with Ben Carterette, Nicola Ferro, and Norbert Fuhr&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Editorial Boards:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Joined the Editorial Board of TOIS&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ongoing service on the Editorial Board of TORS&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ongoing service as a guest editor of a special issue in TORS, with Eva Zangerle and Alan Said&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Member of PhD Defense committees:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=rE1GomgAAAAJ" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Shabnam Najafian&lt;/a> at TU Delft, The Netherlands&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=Nii1zPUAAAAJ" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Naieme Hazrati&lt;/a> at Free University of Bozen-Bolzano, Italy&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://yliang.me" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Yu Liang&lt;/a> at Eindhoven University of Technology and JADS, The Netherlands&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=YAyP5psAAAAJ" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Darius Afchar&lt;/a> at Sorbonne University and Deezer, France&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>(Meta-)Reviewing:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Meta-Reviewing activities for the 2023 conferences ECIS, ISMIR, CHI, SIGIR, RecSys, and CIKM&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Reviewing activities for the 2ß23 conferences UMAP, HICSS, BIAS, ICWSM, MuRS, HC-MIR, CIKM, and IUI&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Reviewing activities for the journals ISR, TORS, TOIS, TKDE, TiiS, CACM&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 international research proposal review&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Session chairing at CIKM, RecSys, and CHI&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Election Supervisor for the SIG UCAI, in the GI group MCI&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Best Paper Award Chair for CHI (Subcommittee Understanding People: Qualitative Methods)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Part of the EXDIGIT Research College recruiting committee at PLUS&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="third-mission--outreach--media">Third mission / outreach / media&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Keynote at FMC in Mannheim, Germany&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Talk at W&amp;amp;K-Forum: Symposion Musik &amp;amp; Mathematik&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 panelist activities: at Expedition KI 2.0, Bzzzz—Konferenz der österreichischen Musikwirtschaft, and the Science Meets Fiction Festival&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Member of the Advisory Board for the Incubation programs FACTORY and FACTORY+ at Innovation Salzburg&lt;/li>
&lt;li>4 media mentions:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1 interview appeared at Backstage PRO&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 interview-based articles appeared at DIE RHEINPFALZ (German) and at ZEITGEISTER&amp;mdash;Das Kulturmagazin des Goethe-Instituts (in German and English)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 short text introducing me as a new professor at Salzburger Nachrichten&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="other-happiness">Other happiness&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Ongoing project (as Co-PI with Karin van Es) with UU&amp;rsquo;s AI &amp;amp; Media Lab and DPG Media. I like our interdisciplinary collaboration.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Going strong with Eva Zangerle and Alan said with the PERSPECTIVES workshop series, a SI in TORS, a TORS paper, and an upcoming Dagstuhl seminar in 2024&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="upcoming-in-2024">Upcoming in 2024&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Our TORS SI will appear in 2024 with two issues.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I will be co-organizing a Dagstuhl seminar and a Dagstuhl perspectives workshop.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In the summer term, I will teach 3 new courses: Recommender Systems 1 in the Data Science Master program, Intelligent Interfaces in the AI Bachelor program, and Contextual Interaction Design (with Chris Frauenberger) in the HCI Master program.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>After a long time due to the pandemic, I started attending concerts again: Spitting Ibex and Hot Pants Road Club Funk Orchestra. It&amp;rsquo;s been a treat.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="the-downsides">The downsides&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>I turned down a job offer and still feel bad about it&amp;hellip;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 desk reject at a journal&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 conference submissions rejected&lt;/li>
&lt;li>We didn&amp;rsquo;t win the bid to organize RecSys 2025.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>After moving back to Austria, I was not very active in playing music.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>It has taken me a while to find an apartment I liked in Salzburg.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The many travels for work and the back-and-forth travel between Utrecht and Vienna in the beginning of the year and between Salzburg and Vienna later in the year got increasingly exhausting.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="wrapup">Wrapup&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I’m pretty sure I’ve forgotten a thing or two or three. Particularly some downsides (is it denial?!).
I want to thank those who supported and encouraged me to move forward, hold my head up high, and uphold integrity.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>