<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Projects | Christine Bauer</title><link>https://chbeu.github.io/project/</link><atom:link href="https://chbeu.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Projects</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2022 Christine Bauer</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://chbeu.github.io/media/sharing.png</url><title>Projects</title><link>https://chbeu.github.io/project/</link></image><item><title>Beyond clicks! Value-driven recommendations</title><link>https://chbeu.github.io/project/beyondclicks/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chbeu.github.io/project/beyondclicks/</guid><description>&lt;p>Many news platforms provides uses with recommendations for a personalized experience that fits their interests and needs.
Providing users with relevant news and a good experience are key to such platforms. However, aside from the consumption of news articles and user loyalty, additional values are relevant; for instance, (political) neutrality, factual news, understandable news, content diversity, and the reach of a broad audience.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Within this research project, we plan to (i) identify relevant values for both the platform provider and the users; (ii) translate and operationalize a selection of these relevant values into new metrics; (iii) test and evaluate recommender systems considering the identified values and metrics.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SpART: Spotlight on Artists in Recommenders Systems</title><link>https://chbeu.github.io/project/spart2020/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chbeu.github.io/project/spart2020/</guid><description>&lt;p>The purpose of this project is to understand how current systems used to recommend music affect artists and to propose alternative solutions that could benefit the artists. The goal is to identify potential problems that affect artists, and to draw on the artists&amp;rsquo; perspective about how future recommender systems could work.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Multi-method evaluation</title><link>https://chbeu.github.io/project/multimethod/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chbeu.github.io/project/multimethod/</guid><description>&lt;p>The comprehensive evaluation of the performance of a system is a complex endeavor: many facets need to be considered in configuring an adequate and effective evaluation setting.
A single evaluation method or measure is not able to evaluate all relevant aspects in a complex setting where a multitude of stakeholders are involved. Employing a multi-method evaluation, where multiple evaluation methods or measures are combined and integrated, allows for getting a richer picture and prevents blind spots in the evaluation outcome.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Together with &lt;a href="https://evazangerle.at" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Eva Zangerle&lt;/a>, I maintain a website on &lt;a href="https://multimethods.info" target="_blank" rel="noopener">multi-method evaluation&lt;/a> where we collect resources that help to apply multi-method evaluation in research and development. Naturally, this collection is meant to grow over time and we are happy to share your resources and discuss best practices.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fine-grained culture-aware music recommender systems</title><link>https://chbeu.github.io/project/fwf579/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chbeu.github.io/project/fwf579/</guid><description>&lt;p>Having tens of millions of musical works available at a listener’s fingertips requires novel recommendation and interaction techniques for music consumption. Thereby the success of a music recommender system, a system that proposes users what to explore or listen to next, depends on its ability to propose the right music, to the right user, at the right moment (i.e., in the right context). However, this task is extremely complex, as various factors influence a user’s music preferences. Amongst others, cultural aspects and characteristics (e.g., different requirements regarding diversity of a playlist or familiarity with its music tracks) have been shown to affect music perception, preferences, and listening behavior. Calling on this, the project entitled “Fine-grained culture-aware music recommender systems” investigates how music recommender systems could and should integrate cultural aspects in order to provide better recommendations. The research findings will answer the question how music recommender systems have to be designed to reflect cultural diversity and will provide insights into cross-cultural music perception, preferences, and listening behavior.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Specifically, the project will investigate the cultural requirements on music recommender systems – as concerns what listeners in different cultures expect with regard to the recommended music. Thereby, we postulate that different granularity levels of culture (e.g., individual, regional, national, or global level) have to be considered to improve music recommender systems. We hypothesize that the various cultural levels of different granularities have to be combined in a comprehensive way to transcend limitations of current music recommender systems. And we will investigate its impact on recommendation quality in cross-cultural studies with users from Austria, the United States, and Korea.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our scientific approach comprises four methodological orientations: (i) a combination of surveys and user panels, (ii) user modeling, (iii) designing and implementing prototypes of culture-aware music recommender systems, and (iv) cross-cultural studies with users to investigate their performance. The samples will include users from the United States, Austria, and Korea; we will focus on national culture, but also consider regional cultures (e.g., urban vs. suburban vs. countryside areas).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In contrast to past research in the field of culture-aware music information retrieval and recommendation, the project follows an approach that is driven by user needs and preferences. The project aims to design and implement music recommender systems that are able to meet those requirements by considering different granularity levels of cultural aspects in a comprehensive way.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>