<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>EXDIGIT | Christine Bauer</title><link>https://christinebauer.eu/tag/exdigit/</link><atom:link href="https://christinebauer.eu/tag/exdigit/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>EXDIGIT</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2023 Christine Bauer</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 09:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://christinebauer.eu/media/sharing.png</url><title>EXDIGIT</title><link>https://christinebauer.eu/tag/exdigit/</link></image><item><title>PostDoc position at Paris Lodron University Salzburg in collaboration with Salzburg Research</title><link>https://christinebauer.eu/post/20230912_postdoc/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christinebauer.eu/post/20230912_postdoc/</guid><description>&lt;p>To strengthen our interdisciplinary research team, we are seeking a full-time PostDoc for 4 years.&lt;br>
This position is part of a collaboration of &lt;a href="https://www.salzburgresearch.at/en/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Salzburg Research&lt;/a> and the &lt;a href="https://www.plus.ac.at/digital-and-analytical-sciences/?lang=en" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Faculty of Digital and Analytical Sciences&lt;/a> at Paris Lodron University Salzburg&amp;mdash;as part of the &amp;lsquo;Excellence in Digital Sciences and Interdisciplinary Technologies&amp;rsquo; (EXDIGIT) initiative.&lt;br>
We are working together at the interface of digitalization, recommender systems, and psychological models and techniques of behavioral change. In an application-oriented basic research endeavor, this position is intended to put a particular focus on questions regarding sustainable and effective mobility and/or tourism.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This position is embedded in the the EXDIGIT Research College with ample room for interdisciplinary collaborations beyond the mentioned focus.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="./job_postdoc.pdf">Full vacancy description (in English)&lt;/a>
&lt;figure >
&lt;div class="d-flex justify-content-center">
&lt;div class="w-100" >&lt;img src="./job_postdoc_featured.png" alt="Pic of full vacancy description; full text in the linked pdf above." loading="lazy" data-zoomable />&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For questions related to the position, feel free to address me directly via e-mail. I am happy to chat if you are at RecSys 2023 and interested in the position.&lt;br>
Applications have to be sent to the e-mail address as specified in the job description.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vacant positions (PhD and Postdoc level) in my team at Paris Lodron University Salzburg</title><link>https://christinebauer.eu/post/20230623_exdigit_jobs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2023 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://christinebauer.eu/post/20230623_exdigit_jobs/</guid><description>&lt;p>I am happy to announce that we have several vacant positions (at PhD and Postdoc level) to work with us within the framework of the EXDIGIT Research College at the Paris-Lodron University of Salzburg.
EXDIGIT stands for &amp;ldquo;Excellence in Digital Sciences and Interdisciplinary Technologies&amp;rdquo;. In this interdisciplinary endeavor, we emphasize bridging the existing research areas and represented disciplines at the faculty.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I seek candidates to work with me on topics related to &lt;strong>fairness of algorithmic decision-making&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>adaptation and personalization&lt;/strong>&amp;mdash;specifically in the &lt;strong>recommender systems&lt;/strong> field. Interest in researching these topics in the music or media sector is a particular asset.
I expect the ability and interest to employ both &lt;strong>computational research approaches&lt;/strong> (e.g., offline evaluation in recommender systems research, data analysis of large data sets) as well as &lt;strong>experimental (user) studies&lt;/strong> (e.g., controlled experiments in the lab or online settings).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The closing date for applications is 31 July 2023.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="./EXDIGIT_C4C_ResearchCollege_deutsch.pdf">Full vacancy description (in German)&lt;/a>&lt;br>
&lt;a href="./C4C_ResearchCollege_final_EN.pdf">Full vacancy description (in English)&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For questions related to the positions on my topics, please address me directly via e-mail.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>In addition to positions related to my favorite research topics, the EXDIGIT Research College has further vacancies on a wide set of topics (both at PhD and Postdoc level). For details, please refer to the full vacancy description.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Warm welcome at the Paris Lodron University Salzburg</title><link>https://christinebauer.eu/post/20230505_sbg/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://christinebauer.eu/post/20230505_sbg/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today, the Paris Lodron University Salzburg gave me a warm welcome by &lt;a href="https://www.plus.ac.at/news/erste-brueckenprofessur-im-projekt-exdigit-an-der-das-fakultaet/?pgrp=218&amp;amp;is_paged=1" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announcing my start on its website&amp;rsquo;s news section&lt;/a> (in German). Thank you!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Appointment at the Paris Lodron University Salzburg</title><link>https://christinebauer.eu/post/20230502_sbg/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://christinebauer.eu/post/20230502_sbg/</guid><description>&lt;p>I am very happy to share that I am appointed professor at the Department of Artificial Intelligence and Human Interfaces (AIHI) at the Paris Lodron University Salzburg, Austria, as of today.
With this appointment, I will join the project &lt;a href="https://uni-salzburg.elsevierpure.com/en/projects/excellence-in-digital-sciences-and-interdisciplinary-technologies" target="_blank" rel="noopener">EXDIGIT (Excellence in Digital Sciences and Interdisciplinary Technologies)&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>