<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>EXDIGIT | Christine Bauer</title><link>https://chbeu.github.io/tag/exdigit/</link><atom:link href="https://chbeu.github.io/tag/exdigit/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>EXDIGIT</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2023 Christine Bauer</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2023 09:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://chbeu.github.io/media/sharing.png</url><title>EXDIGIT</title><link>https://chbeu.github.io/tag/exdigit/</link></image><item><title>Vacant positions (PhD and Postdoc level) in my team at Paris Lodron University Salzburg</title><link>https://chbeu.github.io/post/20230623_exdigit_jobs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2023 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://chbeu.github.io/post/20230623_exdigit_jobs/</guid><description>&lt;p>I am happy to announce that we have several vacant positions (at PhD and Postdoc level) to work with us within the framework of the EXDIGIT Research College at the Paris-Lodron University of Salzburg.
EXDIGIT stands for &amp;ldquo;Excellence in Digital Sciences and Interdisciplinary Technologies&amp;rdquo;. In this interdisciplinary endeavor, we put a particular emphasis on bridging the existing research areas and represented disciplines at the faculty.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am particularly seeking for candidates to work with me on topics related to &lt;strong>fairness of algorithmic decision-making&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>adaptation and personalization&lt;/strong>&amp;mdash;specifically in the &lt;strong>recommender systems&lt;/strong> field. Interest in the researching these topics in the music or media sector is a particular asset.
I expect the ability and interest to employ both, &lt;strong>computational research approaches&lt;/strong> (e.g., offline evaluation in recommender systems research, data analysis of large data sets) as well &lt;strong>experimental (user) studies&lt;/strong> (e.g., controlled experiments in the lab or in online settings).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The closing date for applications is 31 July 2023.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.plus.ac.at/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/EXDIGIT_C4C_ResearchCollege_deutsch.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Full vacancy description (in German)&lt;/a>&lt;br>
&lt;a href="./C4C_ResearchCollege_final_EN.pdf">Full vacancy description (in English)&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For questions, please address me directly via e-mail.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Warm welcome at the Paris Lodron University Salzburg</title><link>https://chbeu.github.io/post/20230505_sbg/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://chbeu.github.io/post/20230505_sbg/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today, the Paris Lodron University Salzburg gave me a warm welcome by &lt;a href="https://www.plus.ac.at/news/erste-brueckenprofessur-im-projekt-exdigit-an-der-das-fakultaet/?pgrp=218&amp;amp;is_paged=1" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announcing my start on its website&amp;rsquo;s news section&lt;/a> (in German). Thank you!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Appointment at the Paris Lodron University Salzburg</title><link>https://chbeu.github.io/post/20230502_sbg/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://chbeu.github.io/post/20230502_sbg/</guid><description>&lt;p>I am very happy to share that I am appointed professor at the Department of Artificial Intelligence and Human Interfaces (AIHI) at the Paris Lodron University Salzburg, Austria, as of today.
With this appointment, I will join the project &lt;a href="https://uni-salzburg.elsevierpure.com/en/projects/excellence-in-digital-sciences-and-interdisciplinary-technologies" target="_blank" rel="noopener">EXDIGIT (Excellence in Digital Sciences and Interdisciplinary Technologies)&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>